<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mini-Projects | Akash Vani</title>
    <link>https://a-vani.github.io/tag/mini-projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-vani.github.io/tag/mini-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Mini-Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Akash Vani 2021-2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-vani.github.io/media/icon_huc8ba58f447d735814d2e3ba3020aeaf2_17412_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Mini-Projects</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/tag/mini-projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning in Astronomy</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/dlastro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/dlastro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This self-guided project aimed to delve into the fundamentals of deep learning techniques using TensorFlow. A simple neural network was devised to classify galaxies as either spiral or elliptical based on photometric data or images extracted from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS). The dataset, provided by Ashish Mahabal during the 7BISS (2020) summer school, facilitated hands-on exploration and learning in the field of astrophysical data analysis. The code can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/A-Vani/Deep_Learning_Astronomy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Key Distribution- BB84 &amp; E91 Protocol</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/qkd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/qkd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project involved the practical demonstration of the BB84 and E91 quantum key distribution (QKD) protocols using IBM&amp;rsquo;s quantum computer. Through hands-on experimentation, we explored the functionality and performance of these protocols, both with and without repeaters, to simulate the operation of a quantum network. By implementing these protocols on real quantum hardware, we gained valuable insights into the practical challenges and capabilities of quantum cryptography. The code can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/A-Vani/IBMQ_QKD&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Polarimetry</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/polarimetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/polarimetry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project encompasses a comprehensive literature survey aimed at gaining insights into the principles and methodologies of polarimetry. It explores the Jones and Stokes formalism and dives into material interactions of light. Additionally, the project included a hands-on laboratory component to facilitate practical understanding. This was concluded with a detailed presentation summarising the findings and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
