<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Major-Projects | Akash Vani</title>
    <link>https://a-vani.github.io/tag/major-projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-vani.github.io/tag/major-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Major-Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Akash Vani 2021-2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-vani.github.io/media/icon_huc8ba58f447d735814d2e3ba3020aeaf2_17412_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Major-Projects</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/tag/major-projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Galaxy Evolution with L-GALAXIES</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/lgal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/lgal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The formation and evolution of galaxies are among the most complex challenges in astrophysics. Recent advancements with instruments like the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) and the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) have shed light on high-redshift galaxies—those that existed billions of years ago. However, most theoretical models, such as the Munich semi-analytical model, also known as L-GALAXIES, are tuned to match galaxies in the local universe and have not been rigorously tested against these early galaxies. Researchers from the Max Planck Institute for Astrophysics and the University of Bonn comprehensively evaluated the L-GALAXIES model using the latest observations and found that while the model aligns well with the properties of local galaxies, it struggles with key aspects of high-redshift galaxies. Particularly, the study highlights critical issues with the model&amp;rsquo;s predictions of quenched galaxies, those that have ceased star formation, including their number density, size and compactness in the early universe, suggesting a need to revise the implementation of processes driving star formation quenching, including supermassive black hole feedback and galaxy mergers. The findings from this research were subsequently published in MNRAS (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2025MNRAS.536..777V/abstract&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fifth Catalogue of Nearby Stars</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/cns5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/cns5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aimed to compile and analyse a comprehensive catalogue of stars within a 25 parsec radius of the Sun. My primary contributions involved early analyses of the catalogue&amp;rsquo;s completeness limit and luminosity function, followed by investigations into local stellar density variations and the properties of the stellar content. The findings from this research were subsequently published in A&amp;amp;A (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202244250&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of stellar populations and white dwarfs in a semi-analytic Milky Way disk model based on Gaia DR3</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/jjmodel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/jjmodel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
This thesis presents the extension of the semi-analytic chemo-dynamic model of the Milky Way disc, known as the JJ model, first presented by Just and Jahreiß (2010), to include white dwarfs (WD). Initially, we test the calibrated JJ model and found minor inconsistencies (about 0.2 % and 2.2 % in 25 pc and 60 pc volume) in total star counts based on Gaia EDR3 data, implying excellent data-to-model consistency. Subsequently, this work incorporated WD synthesis into the model using BaSTI DA and DB (carbon-oxygen core) isochrones and an initial-final mass relation. This work also modeled stellar lifetimes and derived an analytical fit for the DA/DB ratio as a function of effective temperature. Additionally, we established a volume-complete sample of Gaia DR3 WDs within 60 pc and found that the updated JJ model over-predicts WDs by 52%, potentially attributed to assumptions regarding the initial mass function (IMF) and star formation rate (SFR). Exploring this dependency on the IMF, we derived a test IMF; however, a thorough MCMC-based model calibration is warranted. This extended JJ model serves as a valuable tool for studying Milky Way evolution, IMF, SFR, and WD kinematics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectral and timing study of LMXB system 4U 1702-429 using Astrosats X-ray data</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/1702/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/1702/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project focuses on conducting a spectral and timing analysis of the X-ray emission originating from the Low Mass X-Ray Binary (LMXB) system 4U 1702-429. Leveraging data obtained from ASTROSAT&amp;rsquo;s LAXPC and SXT instruments, the investigation aims to shed light on the characteristics of a thermonuclear (Type-I) X-ray burst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CPT synthesis of layered BiOI nanodiscs and its photocatalytic applications</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/cpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/cpt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
Bismuth Oxyiodide (BiOI) is a promising photocatalytic material with exceptional electrical and optical properties, suitable for decomposing pollutants in aqueous systems. This project focuses on the synthesis of BiOI nanodiscs via the co-precipitation method, followed by thorough characterisation using X-ray diffraction and scanning electron microscopy techniques to confirm the formation of nanostructures. Subsequently, the photocatalytic properties of the synthesised material were investigated. This project, led by S. Patil, served as the foundation for his bachelor thesis.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric Calibration of UVIT</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/uvit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/uvit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photometric calibrations are essential for accurately determining the photometric magnitudes of celestial objects. This thesis focuses on the calibration procedures for the Ultraviolet Imaging Telescope (UVIT) onboard ASTROSAT. The aim is to obtain precise estimates of the photon counts per second (C/S) in UVIT filters for calibration sources, including the white dwarf HZ4 and the open cluster NGC188. The procedures involve correcting for instrumental effects such as saturation and spatial variation of sensitivity. Emphasis is placed on evaluating the effectiveness of flat field correction techniques in minimizing spatial variations, ultimately leading to improved photometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
