<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thesis | Akash Vani</title>
    <link>https://a-vani.github.io/tag/thesis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-vani.github.io/tag/thesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Thesis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Akash Vani 2021-2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-vani.github.io/media/icon_huc8ba58f447d735814d2e3ba3020aeaf2_17412_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Thesis</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/tag/thesis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of stellar populations and white dwarfs in a semi-analytic Milky Way disk model based on Gaia DR3</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/jjmodel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/jjmodel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
This thesis presents the extension of the semi-analytic chemo-dynamic model of the Milky Way disc, known as the JJ model, first presented by Just and Jahreiß (2010), to include white dwarfs (WD). Initially, we test the calibrated JJ model and found minor inconsistencies (about 0.2 % and 2.2 % in 25 pc and 60 pc volume) in total star counts based on Gaia EDR3 data, implying excellent data-to-model consistency. Subsequently, this work incorporated WD synthesis into the model using BaSTI DA and DB (carbon-oxygen core) isochrones and an initial-final mass relation. This work also modeled stellar lifetimes and derived an analytical fit for the DA/DB ratio as a function of effective temperature. Additionally, we established a volume-complete sample of Gaia DR3 WDs within 60 pc and found that the updated JJ model over-predicts WDs by 52%, potentially attributed to assumptions regarding the initial mass function (IMF) and star formation rate (SFR). Exploring this dependency on the IMF, we derived a test IMF; however, a thorough MCMC-based model calibration is warranted. This extended JJ model serves as a valuable tool for studying Milky Way evolution, IMF, SFR, and WD kinematics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photometric Calibration of UVIT</title>
      <link>https://a-vani.github.io/project/uvit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-vani.github.io/project/uvit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photometric calibrations are essential for accurately determining the photometric magnitudes of celestial objects. This thesis focuses on the calibration procedures for the Ultraviolet Imaging Telescope (UVIT) onboard ASTROSAT. The aim is to obtain precise estimates of the photon counts per second (C/S) in UVIT filters for calibration sources, including the white dwarf HZ4 and the open cluster NGC188. The procedures involve correcting for instrumental effects such as saturation and spatial variation of sensitivity. Emphasis is placed on evaluating the effectiveness of flat field correction techniques in minimizing spatial variations, ultimately leading to improved photometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
